# **ALEX POMA**

# Senior Software Engineer

+51 973119856

alex.poma.iis@gmail.com

alexpoma.github.io





I'm passionate about data, I'm currently working at TCS as a Data Engineer for a RIMAC Seguros project. I consider myself a self-taught person, who loves technology and process automation, I have several years working with data, ease of working as a team, efficiently solve problems and achieve the productivity goals set by the company and my work group.

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## **Data Engineer**

TCS - RIMAC | Nov 2020 - Now

I'm part of the Tribu Data, a member of the AWS Support team, responsible for creating and maintaining different data pipelines using Cloud technologies and SCRUM methodologies.

- Part of the RIMAC Seguros project for the implementation of the BigData ecosystems on AWS.
- Create workflows using AWS Step Function.
- Creation of Python Jobs on AWS Glue for data processing automation.
- Triggers generation in AWS Lambda.
- Scheduling works with AWS CloudWatch.
- Creation of tables and scripts in Athena and Redshift.
- Implementation and optimization of scripts in Presto SQL.
- Logs review, correction and optimization of potential errors.
- Creation and optimization of Dashboards using Power Bl.
- Use of Agile methodologies complemented with Scrum.

AWS | Lambda | Glue | Step Function | CloudWatch | Athena | Redshift | Python | Presto SQL | PowerBI | Power Automate

## **Business Intelligence Analyst**

CMAC Tacna | Jun 2018 - Nov 2020

Inside the Caja Tacna I had the opportunity to learn many things about the financial system, also to being part of the Business Intelligence and Analytical Solutions area, where I was able to generate and optimize Scripts in SQLServer, use ETL tools to create OLAP cubes and the generation of Power BI Dashboards.

- Implementation and administration of the Data Warehouse.
- Generation of credit reports using SSRS.
- Generation of data load packages using SSIS.
- Implementation of OLAP Cubes using SSAS, for the generation of managerial reports.
- Automating the SBS Data Extraction Process using SSIS and R.
- Times reduction for the generation of financial periods, with the implementation of an OLAP Cube.
- Implementation of Dashboards using Power BI.
- Generation and improvement of Scripts in SQL Server.
- Implementation of the Sinergia project that covers the most used and most important reports and management boards for the company's decision making.

SSIS | SSRS | SSAS | PowerBI | MSQL Server | R | DAX | MDX

#### Technical Assistance - ML Developer

UNJBG - H20 | Sep 2020 - Jul 2021

Support the Water Research group of the Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University, generating statistical and machine learning models, using R and Python.

- Multiple statistical graphs were created using R and Python, using the researchers specifications.
- Automate multiple manual processes so allow researchers focus on data analysis.
- Shiny UI with interactive graphics were generated.
- I have created Notebooks in Jupyter and R Markdown.
- A Neural Networks model was developed using TensorFlow for Evapotranspiration prediction.

Python | R | Shiny | Jupyter | Neural Network | Machine Learning

# **SKILLS**

#### **Technical**

Python/SQL/R

AWS/GCP

Spark/Airflow

Big Data

**Data Pipelines** 

Machine Learning

Data Visualization

#### **Professional**

Effective communication

Teamwork

Problem solver

Good time management

## **EDUCATION**

## Eng. in Computer Science and Systems

Jorge Basadre Grohmann National University

2011 - 2015

# **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native)

English (Professional)

Portugués (Professional)

## **INTERESES**

Swimming

Photography

Programming

Cartoons

